Guide to the Stephen Tennant Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Stephen Tennant papers
1920-2010
OSB MSS 187
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
7.62
(14 boxes)
Tennant, Stephen
Immediate Source of Acquisition
15 August 2011 Acquisition: Purchased from Glenn Horowitz Bookseller, Inc. on the James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn Collection Fund, 2011.
18 August 2011 Acquisition: Purchased from Maggs Brothers Ltd. on the James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn Collection Fund, 2011.
1 August 2011 Acquisition: Purchased from Peter Harrington on the James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn Collection Fund, 2011.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Stephen Tennant
Stephen Tennant (1906 - 1987) was a British socialite and writer known as one of the "Bright Young People," a group of upper-class British artists, writers, and bon vivants during the 1920s. Tennant's friends and peers included Cecil Beaton and Rex Whistler and he had a brief, passionate affair with the poet Siegfried Sassoon. He befriended his favorite author, Willa Cather, and became a travelling companion to her partner, Edith Lewis, and he enjoyed close friendships with Daphne Du Maurier, Stephen Spender, Vita Sackville-West, and Elizabeth Bowen. Later in life Tennant withdrew from society, confining himself to his country estate for decades, producing sheaves of handwritten pages for a unfinished novel, "Lascar."
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, writings, printed material, artwork, and other related papers
Arrangement
Organized into three groupings: 15 August 2011 Acquisition, 18 August 2011 Acquisition, and 1 August 2011 Acquisition.
Tennant, Stephen
- 15 August 2011 acquisition, circa 1920s-2010; 6.63; (8 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence, writings, printed material, artwork, and other related papers.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Purchased from Glenn Horowitz Bookseller, Inc. on the James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn Collection Fund, 2011.
  - Writings, and related correspondence, circa 1920s-1970s
    - Lascar, 5 (Box 1)
      Unpublished novel by Stephen Tennant. Contains: typescripts, manuscripts and various notes. Included are scene-directions, plot summaries and character analyses.
    - Gracie and Gerald, 6 (Box 1)
      Unpublished novel by Stephen Tennant. Contains: typescript and carbon copies, as well as a manuscripts.
    - The Second Chance, 4 (Box 1)
      Contains: typescripts, manuscripts and various notes.
    - "A Reassessment of Poetry" - Introduction to the Volume of Poetry, Call Rapture by its Name (Box 1)
    - My Brother Aquarius, circa 1960s (Box 1)
      Contains: page proofs, manuscripts, and various notes. My Brother Aquarius was privately printed in 1961.
    - 'Madame is Resting', and other prose (Box 1)
      Also contains: 'The Lynx (The Wildcat)', 'But in Brief Longing' - a novel, 'The Public Rose Garden', 'With Canada on his Arm', 'The Night Nurse', and 'Edward & Nannie'.
    - 'The Voice of the Lagoon', and other prose (Box 1)
      Also contains: 'Wuffa: An Anglo-Saxon Fantasy', 'The Japanese Garden', 'Wake, wild visionary' - a poetic drama, 'The Hour Approaches', 'The Treat', and 'Garth Trevor Mattersaunt'.
    - 'A Carriage for Miss Creighton', and other prose (Box 1)
      Also contains: 'The Oriental Goods Store', 'The Exile' - a play, 'The Promise', 'Child Vision', and 'A Portrait of Modern Family Life'.
    - 'The Road Beyond Death' by Dr. Hugo Fischer, and other prose (Box 1)
      Hugo Fischer (1897-1975) was a German philospher, and resident of England between 1925-1938. Folder also contains: 'The Hepworths' - a short story, 'The Memory of a Crime', 'Old Glass' - a short story, 'The Promise' - a play, 'Tomorrow' - a short story, 'One Hour to Kill' - a comedy thriller, 'Holiday Love' - short story, 'The Old Man's Child', 'Man of the World', 'Poor Miss Taffy' - a short story, 'The Man Himself', 'Next Gentleman, please', and 'Luxury Item'.
    - Various untiled plays, short stories and a ballet, circa 1920s (Box 1)
    - 'Evening Reverie', and other prose, circa 1940s-1970s (Box 1)
      Also contains: 'The Curious Sea', 'England and Poetry', 'Pink Cherry Trees, near Portsmouth', 'Sacred Spring. 1971', 'Foxgloves', 'The Question - A Mystery Poem', 'Gloriana's Galaxy - The Mystery of Shakespeare', 'The Joy of Laughing, Hungry as a Hunter', Intellectual Pleasure', 'The Hero', 'Great Love; Son of Joy', 'Spiders', 'To A Wren', 'From Generation to Generation', 'Doubting Thomas', 'In Every Room', 'The Welcome', 'By Candlelight', 'O Ancient Curse of Poets', 'New York in the first Snowfall - The Polar Star', '19, Union Square West, the smell of New York' for Tennessee Williams, for Roger Straus', 'Eighth Avenue. New York City', New York' (?), untitled poem about New York, 'Letter to Mr. Nash (Bournemouth printer)', 'New York in Spring Transition', untitled poem about New York (2 May), 'Essay on Writing', 'An Essay on Pornography', Essay on 'English History' and 'The Seven Bishops', 'What is Law, & what is the administration of it' - an essay, 'A Perfect Rose' - a short story, Anna de Noailles, notes on Willa Cather, and 'Miscellany'.
    - Miscellaneous writings: diaries, journals, and notes on poems, circa 1920s-1940s (Box 2)
    - Short stories and poems (Box 2)
      Contains: 'Venetian Boatman's Song', 'Raiders over the Danube' - a short story, 'Frontier Town' - a short story, 'Decoration' - a short story, 'Mr. Tully's Revenge' - a short story, 'There is my delight' and 'Silence', 'Hot September Day', 'Brown Thistles', 'The Beauty of Silence', 'Early Spring', 'The Sea and Solitude', 'On the Lover', 'Fujiama', 'Storm in an old Garden', 'On the dotted line', 'A Portrait in Cameo - A Crown of Words - for Edinburgh', 'The Consolation', 'Espana', 'Night Convoy on the Uplands', 'Sacquara' - a dull silver poem, 'Renferries Hall', 'The Clock in the Arcade' - a story, an untitled story, 'The World Wakes Early', 'Two Poems for Christmas', and various other miscellaneous works.
    - Poetry dedicated to: Walter Rushmore, and others (Box 2)
      Also contains poetry dedicated to: Bruce Chatwin (writer, 1940-1988), Tim Batsford, Marie Belloc Lowndes (novelist, 1868-1947), Stephen Vincent Benét (writer, 1898-1943), Sir John Betjeman (poet, 1906-1984), Dr. Brian Batten (Stephen Tennant's doctor), Fred Burdett, Joan Collins (actress, 1933- ), Peter Croft, Emily Dickinson (poet, 1830-1886), E.M. Foster (writer, 1879-1970), Simon Fleet (neighbor, 1913-1966), Robert Frost (poet, 1874-1963), Pauline Graham, Chester Kallman (poet and lover of W.H. Auden, 1921-1975), Sidney Keyes, Philip Larkin (poet, 1922-1985), Edna St. Vincent Millay (writer, 1892-1950), Peter Owen (publisher), John Pitt-Rivers (neighbor), Ruth Pitter (poet, 1897-1992), Walter Rushmore, and Derek Salbeg.
    - Poetry Dedications (Box 2)
      Contains: poems referring to Dylan Thomas (poet, 1914-1953), Sir William Walton (composer, 1902-1983), Laurence Whistler (glass engraver, 1912-2000) and his wife Therea Furse, L.W. [Lawrence Whistler?], Mary Wilson (poet, wife of Harold Wilson, British Prime Minister), Wilkie (?), and Elinor Wylie (poet, 1885-1928). Also includes various posthumous dedications, to John Keats, Virigina Woolf, Rupert Brooke, T.S. Eliot, and Cavafy.
    - Poetry (dedicated, but not identified) (Box 2)
      Contains dedications to: Jonathan Cape, Leslie Hotson, Laurie [Lawrence Whistler?], Ivry (Lady) Freyberg, Arvid de Bodisco (Estonian writer), Franze Lehar, Sir Arthur Bryant (historian, 1899-1985), Garcia Lorca, Martin Hynes, Deborah Taylour, Ina Claire (actress, 1892-1985), P.N. Furbank (biographer of Forster), Gervaise Jackson-Stops (architectural historian), Editor of A.A. Chronicle, Elizabeth and Susan Belloc Lowndes, Wilfred Owen (poet), T. Parkinson, Sir Robert Helpmann (dancer, 1909-1986), Diana Menuhin (ballerina, as Diana Gould, wife of Yehudi Menuhin), Bernice Slote (Willa Cather scholor), Rosemary and Joan Oliver (neighbors, nieces of Edith Olivier), Barbara Hutton (heiress, 1913-1979), Anne Marie Gilbert, and various unknown dedications.
    - Lady Head letters, 1928-1929 (Box 2)
      Ruth Mayhew (d. 1939) was the wife of Sir Henry Head (1861-1940), a neurologist and old friend of Siegfried Sassoon's, whom he met through Dr. Rivers. These letters contain references to Sassoon.
    - Edith Lewis, and related correspondence, 1947-1972; 2 (Box 2)
      Edith Lewis (1883-1972) was the friend and companion of Willa Cather. After Cather's death in 1947, Edith Lewis' friendship with Stephen Tennant grew. Edith Lewis and Stephen Tennant shared travels together throughout Europe and the Pacific.
  - Correspondence and poetry, 1940s-1980s
    Mostly alphabetical correspondence to and from Stephen Tennant, with poems dedicated by Stephen Tennant to various individuals.
    - A-B, circa 1960s; 2 (Box 2)
      Contains material related to: Lady Christabel Aberconway (1890-1970), Baroness (Lady Violet Bonham Carter) Asquith of Yarnbury (1887-1969), W.H. Auden (1907-1973), James Bailey (1922-1981), Joan Barton (1908-1988), Henry, 6th Marquess of Bath (1905-1992), and Virginia Marchioness of Bath (1917-2003).
    - B (Bennet) (Box 2)
      Contains material related to: Mildred Bennet (1909-1989).
    - B-C (Box 2)
      Contains material related to: Canon Edward Brewer Brooks (1913-1986), Sir Arthur Bryant (1899-1985), Lord David Cecil, CH (1902-1986), and Frances Cornford (1886-1960).
    - D, circa 1940s-1970s (Box 2)
      Contains material related to: Deborah, Dowager Duchess of Devonshire, Anthony d'Offay, William Arlington Donohoe, and Sir Michael Duff (1907-1980).
    - F, circa 1960s (Box 2)
      Contains material related to: Simon Fleet (1913-1966), Lady Ivry Freyberg, Sir Ralph (1887-1973) and Lady Celia (18..-1975) Furse, and Theresa Furse (1927-2007).
    - G (Box 2)
      Contains material related to: Anne Marie Gilbert, Lord Christopher Glenconner (1899-1983) and John Guest (1911-1997).
    - H (Box 2)
      Contains material related to: Sir Roy Harrod (1900-1978) and Lady Billa Harrod (1911-2005), L.P. Hartley (1895-1972), Christopher Hassall (1912-1963), Ian Henderson, Sir Michael Holroyd, Eileen Hose (1919-1987), and Barbara Hutton (1913-1979).
    - H (Huxley), 2 (Box 2)
      Contains material related to: Sir Julian Huxley (1887-1975) and Lady Juliette Huxley (1898-1994).
    - I-L, 2 (Box 3)
      Contains material related to: Elizabeth, Countess of Iddesleigh (1900-1991), Sandra Jobson Darroch, James Laughlin (1914-1997), John Lehmann (1907-1987), and Rosamond Lehmann (1901-1990).
    - M, 2 (Box 3)
      Contains material related to: Peter Maas (1929-2001) and his wife Marjorie Maas, Lilian McCartney, Alexander B. Macdonald and his wife Dorothy Ann Macdonald, Jamie Maclean, Madame Odette Massigli, and George Matthews.
    - M-O (Box 3)
      Contains material related to: Lady Menuhin (1912-2003), James Mitchell (1939-1985), Victor Musgrave (1919-1984), Diana Ogg, Kathleen O'Hara, and Stanley Olson (1947-1989).
    - P-R (Box 3)
      Contains material related to: Henry, 17th Earl of Pembroke and Montgomery (1939-2003) and Claire, Countess of Pembroke and Montgomery, Ruth Pitter (1897-1992), Patrick Procktor (1936-2003), Sir Peter Quennell (1905-1993), and Lady Pauline Rumbold (1929-2008).
    - S (Box 3)
      Contains material related to: George St. John and his wife Clara St. John, Peter St. John, Richard W. Schuele, Norah Smallwood (1909-1984), and David Spencer and his friend Bruno.
    - S-U (Box 3)
      Contains material related to: Gavin Stamp, James Stern (1904-1993) and his wife Tania Stern (1904-1995), Pamela Street, Mark, 5th Lord Tennyson (1920-2006), Lady Silvy Thynne McQuiston, and John Udal.
    - V (Vickers), 2 (Box 3)
      Contains material related to: Hugo Vickers, DL.
    - V-W, 2 (Box 3)
      Contains material related to: Diana Vreeland (1903-1989), Victor White (1902-1960), and Linda Colin Wileman.
    - W (Wishart), 2 (Box 3)
      Contains material related to: Michael Wishart (1928-1996).
    - W-Y (Box 3)
      Contains material related to: Lucia Woods Lindley, and Patricia Lee Yongue.
  - Correspondence, 1940s-1980s
    Mostly alphabetical correspondence to and from Stephen Tennant, with occasional poems by him.
    - A-B (Box 3)
      Contains material related to: Raymond Abner, J.R. Ackerley (1886-1967), Edith Alexander, Kenneth Anger, 7th Marquess of Anglesey, Dulcibella Atkey, Countess of Avon, Don Barchardy, Francis Bacon (1909-1992), Hermione Baddeley (1906-1986), Lady Janet Bailey (1886-1972), Fitzwilliam Barrington, Patrick Barthropp, Dr. Brian Batten, Florence Beerbohm Kahn (1878-1951), and Gladys M. Bell
    - A-B (Box 4)
      Contains material related to: Susan Belloc Lowndes Marques (1907-1993), Princess Marthe Bibesco (1886-1973), A. Billow, Sylvia Blandford, Anthony Blond (1928-2008), Edmund Blunden (1896-1974), E.S. Bradburne, Martin Breese, Richard Buckle (1916-2001), and Sir Philip Burne-Jones (1861-1929).
    - C-D, 2 (Box 4)
      Contains material related to: Joyce Carey (1898-1993), Ken Cavendish, Anthony L. Chapman, Bruce Chatwin (1940-1989), Paul Chipchase, Mrs. Esmée Christie-Miller, Cipriano and Cicely Clarke, Lady Colefax (1874-1950), Cyril Connolly (1903-1974), Ivy Cooper, Dr. Stewart R. Craggs, Ruth Crone, Anne Crookshank, Bert Crowther, G.A. David, Dr. Anthony Davies and his wife Peggy Davies, Sophie M. Davies, Peter Davis, Baronne de Courcel, Marquis de Cuevas (1885-1961), Richard de le Mere, Paul Delaney, Isabelle de Meaux, Hero de Rance, George Dix, A. Doderet, Norah Doe, Mary Duclaux (1857-1944), and Lady Juliet Duff (1881-1965).
    - E-G (Box 4)
      Contains material related to: Eddie (no surname), 2nd Baron Egremont, Baroness Elliot of Harwood (1899-1994), Sir Jacob Epstein (1880-1959), Aligi Fanncco, Rev. Walter Gordon Emrys Evans, John Farrar (1896-1974), Daniel Farson (1927-1997), Virginia Faulkner (1913-1980), Colin Fenton, Ronald Firbank (1886-1926), Margery Fisher (1913-1992), Dame Margot Fonteyn (1919-1991), Louis Ford and his wife Flora Ford, Lady Edith Foxwell, P.W. Furbank, André Gide (1869-1951), Ram Gopal (1920-2003), Dr. A.R. Gottfried, Sylvia Grant, and Elizabeth, Lady Glenconner.
    - H-K, 2 (Box 4)
      Contains material related to: Hamish Hamilton (1900-1988), Professor Dr. Karl Hansen (1893-1962), Hon. Mrs. Vere Harmsworth, A.M. Harris, Pamela Harris, Sir Rupert Hart-Davis (1907-1999), Nicky Haslam, Marie Helvin, Lady Emma Herbert, Sir Harold Hillier (1905-1985), Tante Johanna Hirth (1889-1977), Charles Howard, Kate Howard, Terri Howard, Christopher Hoyt, Kathleen E. Intz, Hon. Pamela Jackson (1907-1994), Gervase Jackson-Stops (1947-1995), Gerald Jarvis (1930-1966), Oscar Johnson and Peter Johnson, Rachel Kempson (1910-2003), Jennifer Kidman, and Boris Kochno (1904-1990).
    - L-N, 3 (Box 4)
      Contains material related to: Lady Pansy Lamb (1904-1999), Constant Lambert (1905-1951), Edwina Lansberry, Donald Lehmkuhl, Cole Lesley (1911-1980), Arthur Lloyd, Sheila Lochhead (1910-1994), Oliver Lodge (1878-1955), Percy Lubbock (1879-1965), James MacGibbon (1912-2000), Colin MacInnes (1914-1976), David Mann, Mrs. Gervase Middleton (1895-1989), Cay Miller, Hon. Nancy Mitford (1904-1973), Mrs. E.E. Montgomery, Robert Moore, Miriam Mountford, Charles A. Munn (1885-1981), Mae Murray (1889-1965), Lady Naipaul (1932-1996), Sir Rex Nan Kivell (1899-1977), Eustace Nash, L.F.N. Nash, and Richard H. Nathanson.
    - O-R, 2 (Box 4)
      Contains material related to: Edith Olivier (1872-1949), Rosemary Olivier (1903-2002), Lady Oonagh Oranmore and Browne (1910-1995), Lady Parker of Waddington (1903-1990), Hon. Desmond Parsons (1910-1937), Tony Pawson, Mary, Countess of Pembroke and Montgomery (1903-1995), Annina Phillips, Michael Pick, Patrick Procktor (1936-2003), Margaret Pullen, Count Lanfranco Rasponi (1912-1983), Michael "Micky" Renshaw (1908-1978), Sir Francis Rose (1909-1979), Sir John Rothenstein (1901-1992), Toby Rowland (1916-1994), Stephen W. Royce, Anthony Roye (1922-1995), Leonard Russell (1906-1974), Dame Margaret Rutherford (1892-1972), and Kathleen, Duchess of Rutland (1894-1989).
    - S, 3 (Box 4)
      Contains material related to: Loudon Sainthill (1919-1969), Elizabeth, Marchioness of Salisbury (1897-1982), Siegfried Sassoon (1886-1967), Theresa Sassoon (1857-1947), Zachary Scott (1914-1965) and his wife Ruth Ford (1911-2009), Charles Scribners, Anne Douglas Sedgwick (1873-1935),Tonio Selwart (1896-2002), John Semple, Lieutenant Nigel Shakespear and Rosalind Shakespear, Elizabeth Shepley-Sergeant (1881-1965), Sir Sacheverell Sitwell (1897-1988), Bernice Slote, Deborah Smith, Sotheby's, Sir Stephen Spender (1909-1995), Martin Steger-Lewis, Steiner and family, Baronessa Maria Ursula Stohrer, Roger Straus (1917-2004), Merlin, 7th Baron Sudeley, and David Sylvester (1924-2001).
    - T-V (Box 4)
      Contains material related to: Alan Tagg (1928-2002), Pearl and Charlie Taylor, Pavel Tchelitchew (1898-1957), Hon. Catherine Tennant, Hon. Clare Tennant (1896-1960), Hon. Edward Wyndham Tennant (1897-1916), Pamela Tennant, Toby Tennant and Lady Emma Tennant, Mrs. Edward A. Thurber (1891-1960), Theresa Tollemache, Carole Trevarthen, Professor Lionel Trilling (1905-1975), Lady Una Troubridge (1887-1963), Thomas Tudor Pole, United States Embassy, Herbert van Thal (1904-1983), Marilou Viggiano, and Henrietta Vineberg.
    - W-Y - "Diana & Paul" - "Business & Clothes" - "Travel", 2 (Box 4)
      Contains material related to: Arthur Waley (1889-1966), Gwenn Walters, Walpurga, Sir Frederick Warner (1918-1995), Peter Watson (1908-1956), Viscountess Ava Waverley (1896-1974), Eudora Welty, Mr. and Mrs. West, Rex Whistler (1905-1944), Violet C. White, Rex Wighton, [Winifred Winship], Jaffrey Workman, Francis Wyndham, Olivia Wyndham (1897-1967), Violet Wyndham (1890-1979), Lady Rose Young (1895-1981), "Diana & Paul", "Business & Clothes", and "Travel".
    - Cecil Beaton, Dame Daphne du Maurier - Wilsford October 1987 (Box 4)
    - Willa Cather, cuttings and poems (Box 5)
    - Correspondence - Poems by other hands - Pamela Grey writings (Box 5)
    - Letters (Copies) addressed to the Greys - Re: twenty-five years (Box 5)
    - Sketches & illustrations - "The Soldier Returns" - drawings & engravings (Box 5)
    - Personal photographs & exhibit at Iolas gallery 1955, 1953-1974 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous - newspaper and magazine cuttings, fragments of printed photographs (Box 5)
    - Papers after the death of Stephen Tennant (Box 5)
  - Writings, 1930s-1970s
    - Box File 1, 3 (Box 5)
      Contains poems written by Stephen Tennant.
    - Box File 2, 5 (Box 5)
    - Box File 3, 4 (Box 5)
      Contains poems written by Stephen Tennant
    - Box File 4 (Box 5)
      Contains poems written by Stephen Tennant. Also contains photographs, artwork, writings and ephemera.
    - Box File 4, 4 (Box 6)
    - Box File 5, 2 (Box 6)
    - Box File 6, 4 (Box 6)
    - Box File 7, 4 (Box 6)
      Contains writings, printed material and unidentified letters.
    - Box File 8, 1950s-1970s; 4 (Box 6)
      Contains wildlife booklets, various art catalogues, and brochures.
    - Box File 9, circa 1931-1934; 3 (Box 6)
      Contains invoices, relating to medical matters, hotels and other miscellaneous subjects.
  - Other materials, 1923-1928, 2010
    - Elinor Wylie, Black Armour, 1923 (Box 7)
      Printed book, inscribed to Stephen Tennant by the author, Elinor Wylie.
    - Elinor Wylie, The Venetian Glass Window, 1926 (Box 7)
      Printed book, with owner's mark: "Stephen Tennant. His book".
    - Elinor Wylie, Mr. Hodge & Mr. Hazard, 1928 (Box 7)
    - Stephen Tennant inventory, circa 2010 (Box 7)
    - Two notebooks, circa 1928 (Box 8)
    - "A Reassessment of Poetry" - Printed article (Box 8)
    - "Rex Whister - Notes for an article by Stephen Tennant" - typescripts (Box 8)
    - Philip Hoare - Notes on Lascar - typescripts (Box 8)
- 18 August 2011 acquisition, circa 1930s-1970s; 0.5; (4 boxes) + 1 art
  Artwork, correspondence, writings, and journal pages.
  Purchased from Maggs Brothers Ltd. on the James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn Collection Fund, 2011.
  - House In The Woods; Port At Rhodes - framed artwork (Box 9 (Oversize))
    Double-sided framed artwork.
  - "Actress. No Longer Young" - pen/watercolor (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - "Violet Vauburgh and Alice Dolysia, drawn from memory" - pen/watercolor (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - "Acapulco" - pen/watercolor (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - "Lascar" - unfinished pen/watercolor (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - "Stephen Spender" - pen/watercolor portrait, 1956 November (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - "For Margaret Cuevas" - pen/watercolor (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - Pen drawings of women in fine clothes (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - "Goisset Mercredi, 6 heures, 24 Sept. 1873 - Rose in the Twilight" - matted drawing (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - "Le parte de Chartreux, Villeneuve Les Avignon Aug. 1934", 1934 August (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - Study of women in fine clothes - pen/watercolor (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - Untitled artwork - pen/watercolor [Lascar?] (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - "Marseille, City of Orillades" - pen/watercolor (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - Cover art for Flesh and Miracle poems - pen/marker (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - Cover art for Flesh and Miracle Poems - pen/watercolor (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - Cover art for Latitude: Old New York - watercolor (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - "Venice Early Morning" cover design for poems (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - "Venice, Early Morning - a cover for my poems" - pen/watercolor (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - Character study [for Lascar?] - pen/watercolor (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - "Rome" - pen/watercolor (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - Cover art for Lascar, A Story of the Maritime Boulevard - pen/watercolor (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - Cover art for Lascar, or Eyes of Night - pen/watercolor (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - Cover art for The Glory of the Sea - pen/watercolor (Box 11 (Oversize))
  - "Ruby glasses at the Copley Plaza Boston, January 1936" - pen/marker, 1936 January (Box 12)
  - Manuscript writings, 5 (Box 12)
  - Pencil drawing - 18th-century woman (Box 12)
  - Pencil drawing with color - 18th-century woman (Box 12)
  - Print, matted - parade in 18th-century city (Box 12)
  - Print, matted - jungle and city (Box 12)
  - Hospital WWII dedication, print, 1940s (Box 12)
  - Andy Warhol's Interview No. 34 - Nikki Giovanni birthday (Box 12)
  - Poems, hand-written and matted (two pages) (Box 12)
  - Print, matted - pen drawing, "faust teste decoration" (Box 12)
  - 2 prints, matted, colored (Box 12)
  - Print, matted - 18th-century man, colored (Box 12)
  - 2 prints, matted - arches (Box 12)
  - 2 prints, matted, colored - theater (Box 12)
  - Print, matted - throne room (Box 12)
  - 2 prints, matted - "Der Dienen Zwenen Herme" (Box 12)
  - Print, matted - Arc de Triumph (Box 12)
  - "The Curtain Call - Mae Murray in Her Heyday, Hollywood, California" (Box 13)
  - Printed devotional prayer in illuminated manuscript style (Box 13)
  - Pages from art book (Box 13)
  - Pages from drawing instructional and The Art of Drawing Trees (Box 13)
  - The Anglo-Portuguese News, 1973 October 13 (Box 13)
  - "The Winged One" poem - manuscript (Box 13)
  - Poems - manuscript, 2 (Box 13)
  - Pencil manuscript on reverse of Les Editions Rombalde (Box 13)
  - "Wake! Wild Visionary!" - manuscript (Box 13)
  - Pencil sketch of 18th-century man (Box 13)
  - Writings - manuscript (Box 13)
- 1 August 2011 acquisition, 1925-1967; 0.42; (1 boxes)
  Letters to Willa Cather and Edith Lewis, with related writings, artwork and printed material.
  Purchased from Peter Harrington on the James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn Collection Fund, 2011.
  - Single page of printed essay (Box 14)
  - "One late summer day" - MS written on cover of "Denkmaler des Theaters", 1967 August (Box 14)